The Good, The Bad and The Stinky.
The Adventures of Elmo in Grouchland is a family, comedy,
adventure film directed by Gary Halvorson.
Elmo loves his fuzzy, well-worn blue blanket more
than anything in the whole world.
However, when Elmo's blanket gets sucked through a colorful, swirling tunnel into Grouchland, the yuckiest
place on earth, Elmo goes on an adventure to Grouchland to retrieve his prized possession.
Elmo / Pestie / Grouch Jailer / Grouch Cab Driver
(voice), played by Kevin Clash.
Huxley, played by Mandy Patinkin.
Queen of Trash, played by Vanessa Williams.
Maria, played by Sonia Manzano.
Gordon, played by Roscoe Orman.
Grizzy / Pestie (voice), played by Stephanie D'Abruzzo.
The Adventures of Elmo in Grouchland (or simply Elmo in Grouchland) is a 1999 American musical adventure comedy film directed by Gary Halvorson (in his
feature directorial debut) from a screenplay written by Mitchell Kriegman and Joey Mazzarino, based on a story conceived by Kriegman.
This was the second of the two theatrical feature films based on the children's television
series Sesame Street, after Sesame Street Presents: Follow That Bird in 1985.
It stars Mandy Patinkin and Vanessa Williams alongside Muppet performers
Kevin Clash, Caroll Spinney, Steve Whitmire, and Frank Oz.
It features songs written by a wide range of songwriters, including Siedah Garrett, Jeff Elmassian, Andy Rehfeldt, Martin
Erskine, Seth Friedman, and Michael & Patty Silversher, with a score composed and conducted by John Debney.
Produced by Columbia Pictures, Jim Henson Pictures, and Children's Television Workshop,
the film was released by Sony Pictures Releasing on October 1, 1999.
The film received mixed to favorable reviews from critics but was a box-office
disappointment, grossing $11.7 million against a budget of more than $26 million.
The film was one of the few Sesame Street productions
produced directly by The Jim Henson Company.
This was the final Muppet feature film to involve Fran Brill and Oz, who retired from being full-time puppeteers the
following years, and the last Muppet film to feature Spinney before his retirement in 2018 and his death in 2019.
The film explores themes of garbage, musical, puppet, puppetry, cookie monster.
The tone is lighthearted.